<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 02:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to auto delete files in AWS s3 every X times interval in Nodejs</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-auto-delete-files-in-aws-s3-every-x-times-interval-in-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 02:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-auto-delete-files-in-aws-s3-every-x-times-interval-in-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>Here is how you can auto delete files from certain bucker in AWS s3 storage every X times interval in Nodejs, whether less than a day, an hour or any time you choose
Raw logic to choose which files to delete Not like MYSQL query, where we have a where clause to run on a query. We have to implement a different strategy for AWS.
The big picture:
 List all the files Collect only where files older than X times Put Keys of selected files in an array delete objest based on this paramter (array of keys)  Initalize the AWS S3 Assume you have .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Amazon S3 error RequestTimeTooSkewed</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-fix-amazon-s3-error-requesttimetooskewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-fix-amazon-s3-error-requesttimetooskewed/</guid>
      <description>Suddenly one of my s3 function i use normally got an error with message RequestTimeTooSkewed. Here is how to fix it
In my case, i use S3 to automate my database backup with Laravel as backend with this error message:
Exception message: Could not connect to disk s3 because: exception &amp;#39;Aws\\S3\\Exception\\S3Exception&amp;#39; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter what backend language do you use, as long as you got this &amp;ldquo;request time too skewed&amp;rdquo; from S3 message, you can solve this by adjust the timezone on your server</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
