<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 03:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to solve docker containers can not be down or stopped or removed - permission denied error</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-solve-docker-containers-can-not-be-down-or-stopped-or-removed-permission-denied-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 03:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-solve-docker-containers-can-not-be-down-or-stopped-or-removed-permission-denied-error/</guid>
      <description>A lot of advice is running aa-remove-unkown or teardown the apparmore. Which I HAVE NO KNOWLEDGE ABOUT apparmore and scared to do anything in HOST level.
So I found much simpler solution (but more hard work).
How to kill docker container from the inside Find you container-name by running docker ps
Run.
docker exec -it &amp;lt;container-name&amp;gt; sh Now you&amp;rsquo;re on a shell, run
kill 1 Verified the docker stop running by run docker ps again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to auto answer yes or no question when installing with apt in docker</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-auto-answer-yes-or-no-question-when-installing-with-apt-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-auto-answer-yes-or-no-question-when-installing-with-apt-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>When running a docker image, sometimes we need to install a package that requires us to answering a yes and no question. But docker will exit because of this.
So we need to &amp;ldquo;auto answer&amp;rdquo; this question for us during installation.
Solution That&amp;rsquo;s where -y command parameter comes
for example, previously I have
RUN apt-get install libreoffice Docker will exit this, because the question mentioned above. So I need to install it with -y parameter to let it auto anwer for me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty folder not copied to docker - folder not found on production</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/empty-folder-not-copied-to-docker-folder-not-found-on-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 03:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/empty-folder-not-copied-to-docker-folder-not-found-on-production/</guid>
      <description>If your empty folder not copied to docker while on production and you getting error folder not found - here is how I solve it
Problem The problem is actually not in docker, but in my case, it&amp;rsquo;s a git issue. Where an empty folder is not copied by my git.
Add empty folder to git To add your empty folder to git, on your empty directory run
touch .gitkeep Then re add, commit and push your changes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print X number of docker logs</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/print-x-number-of-docker-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 02:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/print-x-number-of-docker-logs/</guid>
      <description>Here is how to print certain amount of logs on docker. It is helpful for me to debug what is happening recently
docker logs -f --tail NUMBER container_name Change NUMBER with how many logs do you want to print, for example we want to show last 10 logs:
docker logs -f --tail 10 container_name What about CONTAINER_NAME ? You can get container name by running docker ps and copy your desired image</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install multiple fonts on docker images</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/install-multiple-fonts-on-docker-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/install-multiple-fonts-on-docker-images/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a way on how to install multiple fonts on your docker images? here is how I did it
... WORKDIR /app COPY fonts ./ RUN mkdir -p /usr/share/fonts/truetype RUN install -m644 ./*.ttf /usr/share/fonts/truetype/ RUN rm ./*.ttf ... Explanation:
 First put all your fonts on fonts folder -&amp;gt; Copy it to docker image Create a new directory to install our fonts /usr/share/fonts/truetype Install with correct permission all *ttf files (assume all you fonts on this file extension) on that new created folder Remove all .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start using mongo shell in docker</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/start-using-mongo-shell-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 22:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/start-using-mongo-shell-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple guide on how to Start using mongo shell in docker.
First, we just need to take the mongo&amp;rsquo;s docker name and run it as interactive shell.
docker exec -it name_of_your_running_mongo_service mongo //-it, is command for interactive shell
Then you&amp;rsquo;re in the shell!
To show all databases, run
show databases; To go inside one of the collections, run:
use collection_name; To list data on one of the collections, run:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
