<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sharing on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/sharing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sharing on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/sharing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hi, hello world!
My name is Hilman, I come from Indonesia! I always want to write a blog in English, but there’s always fear and shame that haunt me. I’m not a native English speaker, so you’ll see (hope not that much) some grammar mistake at first. I’ll keep practice and make it better.
Little bit about me I’ve been a web developer since 2015, and realize how use useful and fun -coding- is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to improve your skill as a developer</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-improve-your-skill-as-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 02:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-improve-your-skill-as-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are writing your first or 1000th line of code, I’m sure we all strive to improve our skill as programmers. We want to do more, learn more, and know more about coding.
How to improve your programming skill? This is the question that we should ask. To answer this question, this article provides a list of how to improve your programming skill
 Disclaimer:
This article generated by AI using copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On building freestuff.dev</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/on-building-freestuff.dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/on-building-freestuff.dev/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I find some free cool developer tools/services that I can use for my next product, I immediately write it down in my private note.
The list got bigger, scroll to it in one file not helping anymore.
I need to categorize it nicely to make it easier to search for something.
Suddenly I thought, why not bring this list public.
I found some links that do the same, but surprisingly not many alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to custom style momentum chrome extensions</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-custom-style-momentum-chrome-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-custom-style-momentum-chrome-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Do you wish to edit or customize any chrome extensions Chrome extensions is just like other program, it&amp;rsquo;s inside your computer after downloaded, so you can customize it too.
In this case i don&amp;rsquo;t like the &amp;ldquo;clock&amp;rdquo; display on my momentum dash extensions. Momentum is a &amp;ldquo;new tab&amp;rdquo; view that will show a hearwarming image + quotes, with todo, quotes and other stuff. Unfortunately , i see the clock is a bit off, and i have clock information everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move My Hugo Site From Github Pages to Netlify</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/move-my-hugo-site-from-github-pages-to-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 08:02:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/move-my-hugo-site-from-github-pages-to-netlify/</guid>
      <description>Today i move my static hugo site from github-pages to netlify. I heard a lot of good things about netlify before, but github-pages seems easier to use (less complicated) for me.
Tiny problem with github-pages Until i found one &amp;ldquo;tiny&amp;rdquo; problem, i can&amp;rsquo;t schedule my post. Since the way github-pages serves our hugo site is by looking what&amp;rsquo;s inside our github public repo, we always have to deploy it manually at the exact time to trigger the changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
