<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git error push remote branch src refspec does not match any</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/git-error-push-remote-branch-src-refspec-does-not-match-any/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/git-error-push-remote-branch-src-refspec-does-not-match-any/</guid>
      <description>If you got error - src refspec does not match any, failed to push some refs to&amp;hellip;- when trying to push change to remote git branch, here is how I solve it
The problem is we haven&amp;rsquo;t connect our git branch to the remote one. It&amp;rsquo;s actually just like when we first initialize our git on main.
What we need to do is using the -u or --set-upstream parameter while push the changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a local branch from existing remote branch</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/create-a-local-branch-from-existing-remote-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/create-a-local-branch-from-existing-remote-branch/</guid>
      <description>If you want to test remote branch locally, you can use fetch method on git to try it on your machine
 First, we need to fetch the remote branch  git fetch origin remote-branch-name remote-branch-name is your branch name on remote Git
What is fetch in Git? Fetch is a command in Git to download commit, files and other info from a remote repository.
Checkout new branch Now, we can checkout a new branch by pointing to the fetched branch above  git checkout -b local-branch origin/remote-branch-name Your local-branch can be any name you want the branch name on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcut bash function to review Github Pull Request locally</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/shortcut-bash-function-to-review-github-pull-request-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/shortcut-bash-function-to-review-github-pull-request-locally/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve learnt how to Checkout Remote Pull Request On Github And Run Locally
But those steps are pretty long to start reviewing changes in our text editor. So I made a bash function for me to save some time:
function checkPR() {git fetch origin pull/&amp;#34;$1&amp;#34;/head:&amp;#34;$2&amp;#34; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git checkout &amp;#34;$2&amp;#34;} usage
checkPR PRNUMBER BRANCH-NAME This way I just need to above function, and directly on the new branch where PR happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add and remove another git remote repository</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-add-and-remove-another-git-remote-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-add-and-remove-another-git-remote-repository/</guid>
      <description>You have an origin remote repository for your git. But you need to add other remote repository. Lets see how to do this
git remote add my_new_name https://github.com/hilmanski/any_remote_repo Now you can verify with
git remote -v It will list all you remote repositories.
To push to this new repo, we can just type
git push my_new_name main *change main, with any branch you want
How to remove git repository Once you don&amp;rsquo;t need a remote repo, you can delete it with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkout remote pull request on Github and run locally</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/checkout-remote-pull-request-on-github-and-run-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/checkout-remote-pull-request-on-github-and-run-locally/</guid>
      <description>If you need to review someones pull request from Github and run the project locally. Check out this guide.
For general method, to fetch any remote changes, please see How to test PR locally
Now, we&amp;rsquo;ll see the step by step to checkout a certain pull request, so we can run it on our machine!
Get the PR number  Either by looking directly on Pull request&amp;rsquo;s tab on Github. To see the number (that comes after the hashtag) Alternative, install github-cli command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test pull request locally</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-test-pull-request-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 21:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-test-pull-request-locally/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re assigned to review your teammate&amp;rsquo;s code from remote git repository. But rather than just reviewing it directly in Github, you want to run it locally first. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can run any pull request locally first and review it.
Use git fetch The first step is running git fetch so we can see get all things that happen remotely on the origin repository.
&amp;ldquo;The git fetch command downloads commits, files, and refs from a remote repository into your local repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove all unsaved / uncommitted changes in github</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/remove-all-unsaved-/-uncommitted-changes-in-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/remove-all-unsaved-/-uncommitted-changes-in-github/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s how to remove all unsaved / uncommitted changes in github. In case you make some changes, and want to get back to the last commit you have
git stash git stash drop </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to remove last commit on github</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-remove-last-commit-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-remove-last-commit-on-github/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s just happened to me yesterday, where I push something to main branch, but not the main branch that I want. I start panicking and looking for help how to undo my last commit before anyone see the changes
The code that safe me
git push -f origin HEAD^:main change &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; with any branch you want.
The result is flawless. People can&amp;rsquo;t see the accident that just happened on you repository 😅</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create simple deploy script</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/create-simple-deploy-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 23:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/create-simple-deploy-script/</guid>
      <description>How many times a day did you do this on command line?
git add . git commit -m &amp;#34;commit msg&amp;#34; git push origin branchName It&amp;rsquo;s my ritual every time I want to push change on remote git repository. As a developer, we always need to find a way how to make our life easier by using our main principle &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Repeat Yourself&amp;rdquo;
Create a deploy script Learn how to create a simple deploy script, to automate your code deployment when using git or any other things in command.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
