<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astro on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/astro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astro on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 23:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/astro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating Hugo site to Astro</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/migrating-hugo-site-to-astro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/migrating-hugo-site-to-astro/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time Hugo fans. But I still struggle on doing certain query, routing or filtering on template in Hugo. I tried Astro and really love it. Here is how you can migrate too
 WARNING
 Don&amp;rsquo;t move if you&amp;rsquo;re already satisfied and don&amp;rsquo;t have any problem with Hugo. If you&amp;rsquo;re working for a long term project AND used to work with react/js environment, give Astro as a shot   Read here, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking a simple comparation between Hugo and Astro</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo vs Astro - which static site generator to choose in 2023</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/hugo-vs-astro-which-static-site-generator-to-choose-in-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/hugo-vs-astro-which-static-site-generator-to-choose-in-2023/</guid>
      <description>Which static site generator to choose in year 2023? should you pick the newcomer Astro or Hugo that been here for a while.
 TLDR;
I have built many sites with Hugo, but I still struggle with the things like integrating 3rd party tools or create a complex query/filter.
Currently, I am trying to migrate a site from Hugo to Astro and I absolutely love the overall experience. So for now, I definitely choose Astro as my main SSG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo shortcode in Astro Components</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/hugo-shortcode-in-astro-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/hugo-shortcode-in-astro-components/</guid>
      <description>Migrating my site from Hugo to Astro, requires me to find out what is a Hugo shortcode relevant in Astro statice site generator.
Astro shortcode-like Astro components is what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. We can make a &amp;ldquo;component&amp;rdquo; (in terms of modern front end javascript library) and use it in our astro file or markdown file.
Read about astro components.
Now is the fun part.. How to use it?
Create a component file We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the detail on separate post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a new file in astro</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-create-a-new-file-in-astro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-create-a-new-file-in-astro/</guid>
      <description>To create a new file in astro site generator, we just need to create a new file inside pages folder with .astro extension
Location
|_ src |_ pages |_ index.astro (default) |_ yournewfile.astro Now you can visit in your URL localhost:3000/yournewfile
Astro automatically pick the file name as your route path
&amp;ldquo;Astro Components (.astro) and Markdown Files (.md) in the src/pages directory automatically become pages on your website.&amp;rdquo; - astro routing</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
