<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-source on Onebite Dev</title>
    <link>https://onebite.dev/topic/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-source on Onebite Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 23:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onebite.dev/topic/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Write HTML dynamically with mini SSG</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/write-html-dynamically-with-mini-ssg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/write-html-dynamically-with-mini-ssg/</guid>
      <description>This is a story about me:
One day, I need to make a simple static website.
Create a folder with ONE HTML file. “index.html”
The next day, I want to add a new file “about.html”, so I make a new file, and then copy-paste all the header, footer, and sidebar to make my pages consistent.
The next day, I need to add a new file again.. again.. and again. Just like before, I need to copy-paste most of the part, let alone the annoying meta tag between head with all the social graph and Twitter cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to improve your skill as a developer</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/how-to-improve-your-skill-as-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 02:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/how-to-improve-your-skill-as-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are writing your first or 1000th line of code, I’m sure we all strive to improve our skill as programmers. We want to do more, learn more, and know more about coding.
How to improve your programming skill? This is the question that we should ask. To answer this question, this article provides a list of how to improve your programming skill
 Disclaimer:
This article generated by AI using copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On building freestuff.dev</title>
      <link>https://onebite.dev/on-building-freestuff.dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onebite.dev/on-building-freestuff.dev/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I find some free cool developer tools/services that I can use for my next product, I immediately write it down in my private note.
The list got bigger, scroll to it in one file not helping anymore.
I need to categorize it nicely to make it easier to search for something.
Suddenly I thought, why not bring this list public.
I found some links that do the same, but surprisingly not many alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
